Lincoln is a history, drama film directed by Steven Spielberg.
The revealing story of the 16th US President's
tumultuous final months in office.
In a nation divided by war and the strong winds of change, Lincoln pursues a course of
action designed to end the war, unite the country and abolish slavery.
With the moral courage and fierce determination to succeed, his choices during
this critical moment will change the fate of generations to come.
Abraham Lincoln, played by Daniel Day-Lewis.
Mary Todd Lincoln, played by Sally Field.
William Seward, played by David Strathairn.
Robert Lincoln, played by Joseph Gordon-Levitt.
W.N. Bilbo, played by James Spader.
Preston Blair, played by Hal Holbrook.
Lincoln is a 2012 American biographical historical drama film directed and produced by Steven
Spielberg, starring Daniel Day-Lewis as United States President Abraham Lincoln.
The film features Sally Field, David Strathairn, Joseph Gordon-Levitt, James
Spader, Hal Holbrook, and Tommy Lee Jones in supporting roles.
Its screenplay by Tony Kushner was loosely based on Doris Kearns Goodwin's 2005 biography Team of Rivals:
The Political Genius of Abraham Lincoln and covers the final four months of Lincoln's life.
The film focuses on President Lincoln's efforts in January 1865 to abolish slavery and involuntary servitude by having the
Thirteenth Amendment to the United States Constitution passed by the United States House of Representatives.
Lincoln was produced by Spielberg and frequent collaborator Kathleen Kennedy, through their
respective production companies, Amblin Entertainment and the Kennedy/Marshall Company.
Filming began October 17, 2011, and ended on December 19, 2011.
It premiered on October 8, 2012, at the New York Film Festival.
The film was co-produced by American companies DreamWorks Pictures, 20th Century Fox
and Participant Media, along with Indian company Reliance Entertainment.
It was distributed theatrically by Walt Disney Studios Motion Pictures through the Touchstone Pictures label in the
United States and Canada on November 16, 2012, and by 20th Century Fox in international territories.
Lincoln was acclaimed by critics, who lauded its acting (especially
Day-Lewis'), Spielberg's direction, and its production values.
It was nominated for seven Golden Globe Awards, including Best Motion Picture – Drama, Best
Director, and winning Best Actor (Motion Picture – Drama) for Day-Lewis.
At the 85th Academy Awards, it received twelve nominations, including Best Picture and Best Director; it
won for Best Production Design and Best Actor for Day-Lewis, his third in the category.
It was also a commercial success, grossing over $275 million at the box office.
It has since been ranked as one of the best films of Spielberg's
career and one of the greatest films of the 21st century.
The film explores themes of mutiny, usa president,
based on true story, speech, battlefield.
The tone is emotional.